Curtis Bowser

Full Stack Developer

SUMMARY

I am a full stack developer who works primarily with React and NextJS, however, I consider myself to be platform agnostic. Different technologies work better with different projects, so it is important to have exposure to many different methods of development. I also have experience Python code for automation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer at Freelance, Salisbury, MD

January 2021 — Present

- Built modern and responsive web applications using best practices
- Built semantically structured full stack web applications
- Used Git and GitHub to manage many projects while continuing their development

Recent Projects:

Gardienne (Live Site) (Fullstack Web App) – Gardienne helps users manage their plants' watering times and improve their health by sending reminders and suggestions. It uses NextJS, TypeScript, React, NextAuth for user authentication, NodeJS, Prisma, and a MongoDB database for storing user information.

Photography Site (Live Site) (React) – This site was built in React and uses Material UI components to display photography. Uses hooks to filter by category and user selection.

React Pokédex (Live Site) (React) – This was built using React with hooks after retrieving the data from the Pokémon API. Users can select and search for Pokémon and brings up information for their choice.

Portfolio (JS) – Features include a dark mode and contact sheet implemented in JavaScript. The site is built from the ground up with HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.

Other Projects: Sentiment predictor, drawing app, BMI calculator, random quote generator, and background color changer.

Driver at DoorDash | Salisbury, MD

December 2020 — Present

Delivered great customer satisfaction with a 5-star rating and zero complaints over my tenure.

Streamer at Twitch | Glen Burnie, MD

January 2018 — December 2019

Grew a community from scratch to 150 followers by increasing awareness through social media and networking. Used viewer data to plan future relevant content.

CONTACT

443.799.1122

bwsrcurtis@gmail.com

Portfolio

Github

LinkedIn

CodePen

SKILLS

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

TypeScript

React

NextJS

Node

MongoDB

Git

OOP

Web Accessibility

EDUCATION

Towson University

Bachelor's of Science

Graduated 2019

Major: Economics